good hello world I never knew Osaka had
such a nice castle and not only the
castle itself but the park surrounding
it the grounds are massive which makes
it a great running course for joggers
the whole area besides inside the castle
itself and the Nishu Gardens are open
24/7 and are free to enter if you visit
Osaka Osaka Castle Park is a must visit
and there will assuredly be a lot of
people visiting Osaka Japan's thirdd
largest city since it'll be hosting the
World Expo 2025 or will have hosted it
depending on when you're watching this
another must visit in my books is the
yam no theater it's located in the
center of Osaka near Osaka
Castle I'll be honest before this I had
only seen no briefly on TV and online
and it looked quite boring to me cool
mask and costumes but I figured the
performances would be quite formal and
use old Japanese that would be hard for
me to understand so when I was offered
the opportunity to experience no I was
hesitant but I decided to try it out
because some special performances have
English translations and backstage
access to the performers stage costumes
and masks how do you feel G and the
giant relief for me was that I
absolutely loved the experience
[Music]
and honestly even if you don't like
history I think you'd have a fantastic
time to get in the theater and start
that fantastic time you have to take
your shoes off and only use socks even
our tripods needed socks and actually it
should have been Tabby socks but they
let our tripod get away with these ones
and if you want to get on the stage
which they actually let anyone do not
just people with a green press pennies
you need to put on Tabby those special
Japanese socks I don't know if they were
being helpful or they thought I couldn't
manage it but they kindly aided me in
putting them
on the stage is a sacred place so it's
not permitted to be on a Barefoot or in
regular socks which is why you wear the
tabi the Yoto theater is a nationally
registered tangible culture property and
a unique thing about it is that it has
balcony seating most theaters are single
story and if you go back a couple
hundred years no stages were located
Outdoors such as within the grounds of
shrines or in The Gardens of large
residences and if you go back a thousand
years no wasn't even called that a
thousand years ago there were various
Arts known as Saku that were introduced
from China after hundreds of years and
many iterations it took on the name of
no and became popular among the samurai
class in 1593 the Supreme General
toyotomi hioshi became fascinated with
the art at the young age of 57 he
performed in the plays himself and
became a patron of no and for a couple
centuries after that no was the
ceremonial art of the government after
the Magi Restoration in the 1860s no
lost its government support and almost
died out instead of being supported by
samai nobility and wealthy merchants
became patrons which enabled the
tradition to continue on to this day
and as of 2008 no became a UNESCO
intangible World cultural heritage so
not only were we taught this history
before the play started we also got a
chance to learn more about the
performers
[Music]
[Applause]
hey
[Music]
complete so now I will show you the no
masks this is
is the
teenagers girl M this
is 20 uh women's face
[Music]
[Applause]
after we learned all about the history
and its performers it was time to see on
a bridg 20-minute version of the play of
which I'll show you a one minute
highlight
H
you
[Music]
[Applause]
you J
[Music]
if you know Japanese and are wondering
why you're having a hard time
understanding don't worry they're
chanting old Japanese that present day
speakers have a difficult time conf
rending which is why these title cards
displayed on the wall are very handy for
both Japanese and English-speaking
audience members after the performance
there was a chance for the audience to
ask questions when the drummers are
singing like is it improvised or the
same every time to answer her question
as there is no director those whoops are
used as a kind of beat to synchronize
the players and singers which may make
you ask why the drums aren't used to
produce that beat to which I have to say
I have no
[Music]
clue the third part of the experience
was the interactive
one being able to get on stage and try
my hand at various aspects quite
deepened my appreciation and respect for
the performers for example with these
masks there's incredibly limited
visibility
you're supposed to slide across the
stage in a smooth manner while holding
your arms out rigidly very unnatural and
if you don't believe me just look at AKO
and how stiff she
looks if this is an example of what a
person normally sees this is how much
you can see when wearing this mask this
tiny little hole the performers have to
learn every square cimer of the stage
and know where they are at all
times and they actually have a little
app that shows off a couple of The Masks
where you can get an idea of what the
mask looks like from behind some masks
will actually have no eye holes and
instead rely on the actor to use his
peripheral vision to orient
himself talking with some of the other
audience members they seem to be having
a ball and I like the effects yeah I
thought that was really cool the webs
the owner of the theater told me that
the spider webs are handmade from paper
and that The Artisans who make them can
only produce a few per
[Music]
day yeah it's my first time to see a
performance live and I was like wow it's
so much better than
online yeah absolutely you need to you
need to hear the sound of the stamp on
the stage
because as I rudely interrupted her to
say you're allowed to go backstage and
not only see behind it but underneath it
also they explain to us that these jars
help the sound reverberate and Echo when
the actor stomp on the exact spot
[Music]
the actually interesting thing is
because of the history for maintaining
the history from almost 300 years and
even some the instrument that they are
using some is all like 300 years some
200 but they still maintain it and
that's very that's very good I think
this is such an important Point these
instruments have been passed on with
care from generation to generation for
hundreds of years because of this
tradition when you're hearing the
instrument you can hear the same sounds
that were played hundreds of years ago
and amazingly unlike a museum where
everything is behind glass you can touch
and play with these historical pieces it
feels like history come
alive
big hold
H
H okay
okay hey it was hot running around
filming on
stage
please okay of course Bobby our
cameraman and editor did it without a
problem right after
[Music]
me
for
for come on oh
I almost forgot to mention that on top
of the performance you can participate
in a te ceremony and then eat the
wagashi and drink the matcha is Mo with
Uncle we are from Brazil so we were
discussing it's not very much possible
to find with the same texture in Brazil
for me it was very interesting it was my
first time so it was beyond my
expectation to learn about Noah it was
very entertaining
all the people at the theater were
incredibly kind helpful and
forgiving now this last thing that I did
this is something that you can pay extra
to experience and it's something that
only I got to do that day I was dressed
up like how the performers are not the
quick drape the costume over you quickly
for a few piics thing the Bowing before
putting on the mask is very important
it's an expression of gratitude to the
spirit of the Mask Creator and the actor
predecessors who have preserved the mask
and pass it down to the following
Generations what I also learned when
putting on the mask is that since the
mask itself doesn't change emotions are
expressed through the Shadows created by
tilting The Mask or a set pose when they
placed my hand like this it represents
me crying when they placed my hand like
this with the fan up it represents that
I'm
[Music]
happy if you fall down I I will
catch uh keep keep the eye yeah keep the
face
just see A's
[Music]
arm for
and after the entire event was done the
owners treated us to kakori a
traditional multi-course meal just
incredible thank you and to V Clair
anyone can book a meal experience like
what we had and you can even reserve the
theater for a private party are meeting
if you
like this no experience was part of the
Japan cultural Expo 2.0 which promotes
the beauty and spirit of Japan so if you
want to have a deep cultural experience
like this one they have many to choose
from so check out their website in the
description thanks for watching see you
next time peace what's musical theater
like where you're from
[Music]